<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pdebashis.com</title>
    <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on pdebashis.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 02:47:09 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pdebashis.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Solving a treacherous bug on a Friday night</title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/bug-resolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 22:34:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/bug-resolution/</guid>
      <description>So, I had been trying to run a simple websocket listener. I had a system in place which will do the authentication and provide me with a wss:// address on which I can add a listener. There are a bunch of libraries to do this. So I copy pasted some code from internet which used the ruby gems faye/websocket and EventMachine and all was good for a while. Till I decided to run this thing on a windows machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Victoria&#39;s Museum, Kolkata</title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/photos/kolkata/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/photos/kolkata/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Resign and then come back </title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/whyback/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 02:02:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/whyback/</guid>
      <description>We don&amp;rsquo;t really appreciate what we have until its gone. I was doing well and I got excited wanting to earn more money and experience new workplaces so I left. I expected any place i go to, to have the same standards and satisfaction of work.
Heck no. I joined a company out in an older part of bangalore that was a marketing analysis/telecom campaigning software company. I thought I was bringing some relevant/current knowledge in to the company that I had learned from other smart engineers I was fortunate to work with in the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Konark, Puri</title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/photos/konark/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/photos/konark/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milestone 1 : 5 years in IT service</title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/milestone1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 01:02:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/milestone1/</guid>
      <description>This month marks the 5th year for me working in IT. The journey so far has been fairly enjoyable. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to put it into words, so here&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of infographics.
All graphics are prepared in MS Paint.
Career Timeline Metrics Chart Travel </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring Hadoop</title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/hadoop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 17:34:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/hadoop/</guid>
      <description>A Hadoop ecosystem requires vigorous monitoring to identify any abnormality and prevent major downtimes. Major Hadoop service providers, provide their own tools for monitoring. But for a standalone hadoop, the monitoring aspect is an open field, and you can use your own tools and scripts to setup a monitoring framework.
Here, lets try to setup a basic script based monitoring capability with essential indicators
Uptime Monitoring Identify each process type running on each cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Type of roles I have come across</title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/careerpath/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 01:02:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/careerpath/</guid>
      <description>These are the different shoes to fill.
programming These people make sure the code matches the design and give feedback into the design process based on their technical knowledge
technical Lead These are over-acheiving programmers who now also have a bunch of programmers to guide
Implementation These people understand the scope of the product and shape it to meet the client needs. This person is required to interface a lot with other teams and the clients</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 02:47:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Debashis. and I&amp;rsquo;m a code monkey. I specialize in cloud computing and big data.
I am inspired by a character named Milo Pressman from the TV show 24. Check him out here.
Currently, I&amp;rsquo;m working on ruby-algorithmic-trading.
If you want to reach out to me, you can do it via GitHub, Discord or Twitch.
If you would like to support me, Please buy me a Coffee</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>