<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on pdebashis.com</title>
    <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on pdebashis.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 17:59:25 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quick Notes : Kafka</title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/kafka/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 17:59:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/kafka/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Consumer Subscribe to a topic and pull messages
Producer Send a message record to a topic
Topic Has a consumer instance
Topic Partition Have individual consumer instance
leader is the node responsible for all reads and writes for the given partition. Each node will be the leader for a randomly selected portion of the partitions.
replicas is the list of nodes that replicate the log for this partition regardless of whether they are the leader or even if they are currently alive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Notes : Hadoop</title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/hadoop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 17:34:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/hadoop/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Collection of opensource software utilities that facilitate using a network of many computers to solve problems involving massive amounts of data and computation. Majorly consisting of a filesystem, atop the file systems comes the MapReduce Engine, an Hbase database and other applications.
Namenode maintains file system namespace. It knows the list of directories and files. It also manages file to block mapping.
Journal Node is a lightweight solution to store namenode edit logs</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where do you want to see yourself in 5 years</title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/fiveyearplan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 01:39:41 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/fiveyearplan/</guid>
      <description>Purpose is unique to each individual. Professionally, I would like to have an indispensable role wherever I am. But where do i want to be in my personal life?
In five years time, I may want to go to the beach. I dont want an expensive indoor movie theater experience at my house. i can just watch a movie on my laptop or TV. I dont want an expensive bmw and have to wash and maintain it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designed to Fail?</title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/failurerecipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 01:20:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/failurerecipe/</guid>
      <description>There are sometimes incidents which is a disaster and should&amp;rsquo;ve/could&amp;rsquo;ve been avoided. Rather than the details of the failure itself, what is more interesting is the way it is handled. The team working on it, sometimes takes a tiny system fault to a gigantic catastrophe through a cascading series of events. At other times, the team is able to take a catastrophic system failure and make a commendable save.
I try to avoid the following -</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My understanding of roles in IT</title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/careerpath/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 01:02:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/careerpath/</guid>
      <description>These are the typical roles I have come across.
programming These people make sure the code matches the design and give feedback into the design process based on their technical knowledge
architecture/design These people figure out the overall technical design that matches the business needs, make tradeoffs between technical purity and practicality (e.g. X sucks but everyone in the company uses X so we have to use it too). This person is required to interface with other teams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I like working on weekends?</title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/weekendpolicy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 00:52:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/weekendpolicy/</guid>
      <description>Weekends are a peaceful way to work with no one standing behind your shoulders. So you can spend appropriate amount of time on a task rather than doing it in a hurry. This leads to better quality of work and I end up enjoying more what of what i do. There is also less emails and chats for distractions.
I relax a lot on weekdays with tea breaks and chit-chats here and there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/firstpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 01:49:53 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/firstpost/</guid>
      <description>Testing Hugo Framework to setup a blog</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
