<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on pdebashis.com</title>
    <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on pdebashis.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 01:02:26 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Milestone 1 : 5 years in IT service</title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/milestone1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 01:02:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/milestone1/</guid>
      <description>This month marks the 5th year for me working in IT. The journey so far has been fairly enjoyable. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to put it into words, so here&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of infographics.
All graphics are prepared in MS Paint.
Career Timeline Metrics Chart Travel </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring Hadoop</title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/hadoop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 17:34:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/hadoop/</guid>
      <description>A Hadoop ecosystem requires vigorous monitoring to identify any abnormality and prevent major downtimes. Major Hadoop service providers, provide their own tools for monitoring. But for a standalone hadoop, the monitoring aspect is an open field, and you can use your own tools and scripts to setup a monitoring framework.
Here, lets try to setup a basic script based monitoring capability with essential indicators
Uptime Monitoring Identify each process type running on each cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Type of roles I have come across</title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/careerpath/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 01:02:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/careerpath/</guid>
      <description>These are the different shoes to fill.
programming These people make sure the code matches the design and give feedback into the design process based on their technical knowledge
technical Lead These are over-acheiving programmers who now also have a bunch of programmers to guide
Implementation These people understand the scope of the product and shape it to meet the client needs. This person is required to interface a lot with other teams and the clients</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/firstpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 01:49:53 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/firstpost/</guid>
      <description>Testing Hugo Framework to setup a blog
Why blog? A lot of time is spent on technical work and their is no other outlet to put it out here on the internet.
Why Hugo? After working on rails for some time, I found the static generated sites (like Hugo) make more sense than having a full backend for a personal portfolio site. I do not have any dynamic content requirements and it was also easier to host.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
