<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on pdebashis</title>
    <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on pdebashis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 01:02:26 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Scala Interview</title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/interview-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 01:02:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/interview-experience/</guid>
      <description>This was a coding interview in Scala. The problem statement was a simple one :
Input = List(10, 10, 10, 10, 20, 30, 30, 10, 10, 40, 50, 50, 50, 50)Output = List(10, 20, 30, 10, 40, 50)Kindly eliminate the consecutive duplicates of the elements contained within this list.Approach 1
My first thought was to implement a temp variable based solution - introduce a &amp;ldquo;memory&amp;rdquo; element which keeps updating when encountering a new number and I ended up writing the below code -</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Deep Dive into my chess.com games</title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/chess-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 22:58:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/chess-analytics/</guid>
      <description>Since I created an account on chess.com in 2020, I have played an unhealthy amount of games on the website and all my games are saved in their database. The trail of data I have created over the years should contain huge secrets of my own gameplay, but the stats I see on my profile are too basic and do not offer useful plans to improve. If I could to decipher more from the data of my games, I could get potential insights into my strengths and weaknesses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up linode Arch Linux</title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/setup-linode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 01:02:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/setup-linode/</guid>
      <description>Blindly run these steps once you have a brand new Arch Linux Server in linode.
Connect to your Linode via SSH:
ssh root@IP Set your timezone and synchronize the hardware clock with the system clock:
ln -sf /usr/share/zoneinfo/Asia/Calcutta /etc/localtimehwclock --systohcdate Create a new user and set sudo permissions:
useradd -m pdebashispasswd pdebashisexport EDITOR=&amp;#34;vim&amp;#34;visudo--- add the line &amp;#34;pdebashis ALL=(ALL) ALL&amp;#34; Switch to the newly created user</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yamaha FZ-S 2017</title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/first-bike/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 01:02:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/first-bike/</guid>
      <description>Purchased new on 16 Jan in 2017, so it has now been more than 6 years owning and riding the bike. I have used it mostly in and around Bangalore. Here is a short ChatGPT generated rhyme about my journey owning the bike, following that are some data points i like to track.
Been ridin’ my Yamaha for six years strong
Got it when I was young, but now I’m grown</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Over the Board Chess Tournament</title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/chess-dreamhack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 01:02:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/chess-dreamhack/</guid>
      <description>This was my first OTB experience. The tournament was - &amp;ldquo;DreamHack Rapid and Blitz&amp;rdquo;, organized by NODWIN Gaming, Samay Raina and ChessBase India. It was a 9RD Swiss, G/15+10 time control for Rapid and was open to all. The prize fund was around Rs.10 lakh and the entry fee at Rs.1299. It was held on 4th and 5th of Novemeber, 2022 in the Hitex Exhibition Centre in Hyderabad.
Tournament Details - https://chess-results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insurance Fraud</title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/fraudulent-selling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 01:49:53 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/fraudulent-selling/</guid>
      <description>Me and my mom, were once approached by 2 insurance agents from bajaj Finance at our home. We had some funds lying with them which they were suggesting to move around. We let them go ahead with these processes. Then she was asked for options on how to invest this amount. We were not interested for anything other than a FD and since Bajaj Finance already had some other FDs for us, we agreed to park this money as well with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flavors of a Software Career</title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/careerpath/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 01:02:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/careerpath/</guid>
      <description>My career has been dynamic over the first few years. I have moved from project to project, within a company and across, up in hierarchy and sideways, creating a matrix of career options for myself. Sometimes the change was fast, at times slow and on some instances even in the wrong direction, but I have now built up a portfolio of experiences.
These are the various hats I have worked as/with and a 5 years old-tier explanation of what each title entitles you to do typically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solving a treacherous bug on a Friday night</title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/bug-resolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 22:34:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/bug-resolution/</guid>
      <description>So, I had been trying to run a simple websocket listener. I had a system in place which will do the authentication and provide me with a wss:// address on which I can add a listener. There are a bunch of libraries to do this. So I copy pasted some code from the internet which used the ruby gems faye/websocket and EventMachine and all was good for a while. Till I decided to run this thing on a Windows machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review : The Big Nine</title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/ai-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 19:49:53 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/ai-book/</guid>
      <description>How the tech titans and their thinking machines could wrap humanity
Notable Qoutes This is the way the world ends, not with a bang but with a whimper. - T.S.Eliot
The first ultraintelligent machine is the last invention that man need ever make.
By not using any human data, Zero&amp;rsquo;s creators removed the constraints of human knowledge. Humans, as it turned out, would have held the system back. - in reference to the Alpha Zero</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competitive Programming memories from University</title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/coding-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 18:49:53 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/coding-competition/</guid>
      <description>Looking back on the days in college where I felt very elated - happy and confident solving programming challenges as a sport.
NMPC was one of the contests, abbreviated from NIST Monthly Programming Contest. It was introduced in my third year at college and was organized only 3 times in 2 years even though the name indicated otherwise. The Sankalp coding contest on the other hand, was an yearly contest and was organized without fail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Resign and then come back </title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/whyback/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 02:02:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/whyback/</guid>
      <description>We don&amp;rsquo;t really appreciate what we have until it&amp;rsquo;s gone. I was having a good time in my first company and I expected any place I go to, to have the same standards and satisfaction of work.
Reality is often dissapointing. I joined a company out in an older part of Bangalore that was a marketing analysis/telecom campaigning organisation. I was put into Customer support, where nobody gave any attention to work culture or work life balance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milestone 1 : 5 years in IT</title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/milestone1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 01:02:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/milestone1/</guid>
      <description>This month marks the 5th year for me working in IT. The journey so far has been fairly enjoyable. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to put it into words, so here are a bunch of infographics.
Graphics are prepared in MS Paint.
Career Timeline Travel </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring Hadoop</title>
      <link>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/hadoop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 17:34:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdebashis.github.io/posts/hadoop/</guid>
      <description>A Hadoop ecosystem requires vigorous monitoring to identify any abnormality and prevent major downtimes. Major Hadoop service providers, provide their own tools for monitoring. But for a standalone hadoop, the monitoring aspect is an open field, and you can use your own tools and scripts to setup a monitoring framework.
Here, lets try to setup a basic script based monitoring capability with essential indicators
Uptime Monitoring Identify each process type running on each cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
